# Ryan Bowler

github.com/ryanbprog ryanbprog.com linkedin.com/in/ryan

A passionate developer and professional problem solver with 10+ years in engineering, driven by a hunger for learning and a deep love for building things. Whether it's crafting a sleek frontend or working with backend logic, I love what I do and I thrive on problem solving.

# **Projects**

My Portfolio (Astro, TypeScript, Tailwind) - View Repo

Provides an in-depth look at my projects, professional experience, and personal background.

Dev Trainer (TypeScript, React, Next.js, Express, MongoDB (Mongoose), Redis, Tailwind, OAuth 2.0, Gemini) - View Repo

Master keyboard shortcuts through personalized lists. Features include custom shortcut organization, an admin panel for content management and AI for generating code snippets.

Better Spanish (TypeScript, React, Next.js, Express, PostgreSQL (Drizzle), Tailwind) - View Repo

Master Spanish faster with a focus on high-frequency words. Features include verb conjugation practice, flashcards with spaced repetition algorithms and personalized progress tracking.

**Dymone** (TypeScript, React, Next.js, Sanity, Stripe, Tailwind) - View Repo

An e-commerce site for a luxury jewellery online retailer, intergrated with Sanity as the CMS and Stripe to process payments and manage products.

# **Work Experience**

## Bruce Rock Engineering - April 2022 to April 2024

- Implemented new engineering design procedures to improve communication and quality of the final product
- Programmed and managed a suite of tools that automated a range of repetitive engineering design tasks
- Managing the engineering drawing processes as a whole

Mettler-Toledo - August 2020 to Jan 2022

- Maintaining and developing new and existing mechanical designs with the use of specialised 3D software
- Managed and evolved an assigned product range as an SME, providing technical guidance and driving design improvements
- Reviewing and auditing others' work to maintain a high design standard across the department

**KMG -** June 2020 to August 2020

Mettler-Toledo - October 2019 to April 2020

(Please visit my LinkedIn to view full career history)

# **Education**

#### **Equinium College**

Diploma of IT (Backend Development)

#### **UniCourse Limited**

Diploma of Engineering (Manufacture)

#### Mota

Frontend Development Certification

## **Advanced Apprenticeship**

Mechanical Engineering (Design)

# **Skills**

Languages: JavaScript/TypeScript, Python, HTML/CSS

Frameworks/Libraries: React, Next.js, Astro, Node.js, MongoDB (Mongoose), Express.js, PostgreSQL (Drizzle), Redis, Sanity, Tailwind, SCSS, Bootstrap, Jest

Tooling: Git, GitHub, VS Code, Google (Gemini, OAuth 2.0), Vercel, Stripe

Soft Skills: Critical thinking, Problem solving, Self-motivating, Management, Hunger for learning